<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-2"?>
<document lang="en">
	<properties>
		<author email="new@foo-baz.com">Pawel Niewiadomski</author>
		<title>Introduction</title>
	</properties>

	<body>
		<section>
		<title>Introduction</title>

		<para>
			Following chapter includes short introduction to this project.
			It includes lisf of requirements and other constraints. There's 
			also a glossary.
		</para>
		
		<para>
			This document is a detailed documentation related to this project.
			It includes: introduction, design considerations, system architecture,
			policies and guidelines, detailed design, glossary, bibliography
			and administrator's guide.
		</para>

		<para>
			Document is for anyone that wants to get familiar with the system.
			Some parts require IT knowledge. Target groups are
			administrators and developers.
		</para>

		<para>
			Full name of the project is Incredible Hosting System,
			acronym is <glossterm>IHS</glossterm>. Usually acronym will be used.
			Main part of IHS is administration panel that allows administrators
			to manage mail system. It was my master thesis.
		</para>
		
		<para>
			To get familiar with this project, made decisions and
			to learn about some products it's worth checking
			my engineer thesis - Free Mail System - NIE-2003.
			IHS is based on experience gained during implementation of previous
			thesis, it's another step to achieve integrated management
			framework for hosting systems.
		</para>
	</chapter>

	<chapter id="overview">
		<title>Overview of the system</title>

		<para>
			IHS will be a platform for implementing and
			integrating mail or hosting systems in different environments - small
			or medium companies looking for tools for managing system accounts,
			hosting companies offering services based on this system.
		</para>

		<para>
			System is complex, requires integration of many other applications,
			for example: WWW server, mail transfer agent, FTP server, database.
			Also it should be possible to integrate system with other applications
			that are specific to company's environment.
		</para>

		<para>
			Aside integration of existing application platform must be built
			that will allow to manage everything is a manner
			undependent from tools that are used in background.
			It should be a centralized and consistent environment.
			Also API for developers shoule be generic that changes
			in tools doesn't require changes in code.
		</para>

		<para>
			IHS will be based on following tools, technologies:
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Apache as WWW server;
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						PostgreSQL as default database;
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						ProFTPD as default database;
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						qmail or Virtual Qmail as a MTA;
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						CORBA as a service communication protocol;
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						J2EE as an runtime environment;
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>

		<para>
			Project is implemented using only open source software,
			source code of this system will be distributed. This will
			allow anyone to modify system for his/her needs. System
			will extendable.
			<ulink url="http://foo-baz.com/">foo-baz.com</ulink>
			company offers services related with installtion,
			integration and maitenace of IHS in clients' environments.
		</para>
	</body>
</document>

